A Guide to the University of Connecituct Centennial Collection 1981.0002
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
University of Connecticut Centennial Collection
undated, 1978-1981
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1981.0002
1.25 Linear Feet
Collection contains significant documentation of the University's Centennial Celebration which took place in the academic year 1980-1981.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The memorabilia for this collection was donated by the Jorgensen Auditorium (Jorgensen Center for the Performing Arts) in September 1981. The correspondence was donated by the President's Office in August 1982.
Scope and Content
The Centennial Collection contains mostly correspondence and memorabilia documenting the 100th anniversary of the establishment of what is now the University of Connecticut. The year 1980-1981 was chosen for the celebration because it was the 100th consecutive year of academic operation at Storrs. The celebration began with Opening Convocation on 23 September 1980, and continued with exhibitions, balls, colloquia, Founder's Day, a newspaper supplement, student events, as well as events held by the individual schools and colleges. The yearlong celebration ended with the Second Century Convocation on 19 September 1981.
For additional material, consult the Connecticut Centennial Coordinating Committee Records available at the reference desk.
Education; Universities and colleges; History; Storrs (inhabited place); Connecticut (state); Correspondence; Publications (documents); University of Connecticut
- Series I: Centennial Records, 1978-1981
  - Correspondence- President's Office, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence- President's Office, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence- President's Office, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Coordinating Committee
    - Minutes, 1980 April - May (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Members (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Fundraising Coordinating Committee
    - Minutes, 1980 September - October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The University of Connecticut Centennial Fund 1980-81, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Calendars, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Centennial Events
    - Opening Convocation, 1980 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - First Annual Convocation Honoring Recently Retired Members of the Faculty and Staff, 1980 October 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Founder's Day: A Centennial Celebration, 1981 April 21
    - Remarks by President DiBiaggio (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Remarks by Dr. A. J. Conzonetti (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Barney House Dinner (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Guest List (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Pamphlets, brochures (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Second Century Convocation, 1981 September 19
    - Brochures (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letters of regret from academic institutions (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Certificates of congratulations from academic institutions
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - Montana State University (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Northeastern University - Polytechnic Institute of New York (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Princeton - Rensselaer (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - University of Chicago - University of Michigan (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - University of Mississippi (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - University of Missouri - University of Washington (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Vanderbilt University (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Vassar College - Wheaton College (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - William Marsh Rice University (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Second Annual Convocation Honoring Recently Retired Faculty and Staff, 1981 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Other centennial events: pamphlets, notices (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Centennial Publications
    - At Issue (School of Social Work Newsletter), 1980 Fall (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Centennial Times, vol. 1, no. 1, 3, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1980 August (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Proceedings (New England-St. Lawrence Valley Geographical Society), 1980 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Second Century University of Connecticut Alumni Association, [1981?] (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "The University of Connecticut- 100 Years of Dedication" - newspaper supplement, 1981 April (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - University of Connecticut Chronicle, vol. 2, no.27, 1981 April 28 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - General mailing letters (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Proclamation: UConn Centennial fortnight in the city of Hartford, 1980 October 6 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Bumper Stickers (Box 3, Folder 38)